In this
lesson,
we're
going to
be
talking
about
finance.
And
one of
the most
important
aspects
of
finance is
interest.
When I go
to a bank
or some
other
lending
institution
to borrow
money, the
bank is
happy
to give
me that
money. But
then I'm
going to
be paying
the bank
for the
privilege
of using
their
money. And
that
amount of
money that
I pay the
bank is
called
interest.
Likewise,
if I put
money
in a
savings
account or
I purchase
a
certificate
of
deposit,
the bank
just
doesn't
put my
money in a
little box
and leave
it there
until
later.
They take
my money
and lend
it to
someone
else. So
they are
using my
money.
The bank
has to pay
me for the
privilege
of using
my money.
Now what
makes
banks
profitable
is the
rate
that they
charge
people to
use the
bank's
money is
higher
than the
rate that
they
pay
people
like me to
use my
money. The
amount of
interest
that a
person
pays or
earns is
dependent
on three
things.
It's
dependent
on how
much money
is
involved.
It's
dependent
upon the
rate of
interest
being
paid or
the rate
of
interest
being
charged.
And it's
also
dependent
upon
how much
time is
involved.
If I have
a loan
and I want
to
decrease
the amount
of
interest
that I'm
going to
pay, then
I'm
either
going to
have to
decrease
how
much
money I
borrow,
I'm going
to have
to borrow
the money
over a
shorter
period
of time,
or I'm
going to
have to
find a
lending
institution
that
charges a
lower
interest
rate. On
the other
hand, if I
want to
earn more
interest
on my
investment,
I'm going
to have to
invest
more
money,
leave the
money in
the
account
for a
longer
period of
time, or
find an
institution
that will
pay
me a
higher
interest
rate.